http://www.whatcom.ctc.edu/about-the-college/policies-procedures/privacy-notice

HomeGet Started
Get Started at WCCCampus Visits & EngagementsAdvising & Career ServicesFinancial AidFind a ClassHigh School Students & CounselorsInformation for ParentsRegistration CalendarRunning StartScholarshipsSummer at WhatcomPlacementTuition & FeesWave Orientation
Academics
Academic DepartmentsCanvasClass Schedule SearchCommunity & Continuing EducationCollege Catalog & Course DescriptionsDegrees & CertificatesHigh School & Middle School ProgramsHonors & AwardsInternational ProgramsLearning OptionsOnline and Evening OptionsPre-College Adult Education & GED
Student Services
Access & Disability ServicesAdmissions & RegistrationBookstoreComputer Access & Tech HelpCounselingFinancial WellnessFunding & Support ProgramsGraduation InformationLGBTQ Student Success InitiativeLibraryMyWCCReturning StudentsStudent ConductStudent SuccessTutoring / Learning CenterUndocumented StudentsVeteran ServicesVirtual One StopVirtual Front Desk
Campus LifeCampus Events CalendarCurrent StudentsDining ServicesFrequently Asked QuestionsFuture StudentsHorizon Student NewspaperIntercultural CenterMeet Our Faculty, Staff & StudentsNoisy Water ReviewOrca AthleticsOrca Student ID CardResidence Life HousingStudent Life and DevelopmentStudent Recreation CenterSustainability at Whatcom
About the CollegeAbout WhatcomArea Health Education Center for Western WashingtonAssessment & AccreditationBusiness & Community PartnershipsCampus Map & DirectionsCollege LeadershipContact Us (Remote Services)Cybersecurity CenterNCyTE CenterDiversity, Equity and InclusionEmergency & Weather InfoEmployment / HRFoundationNews & MediaPolicies & ProceduresRequest Info PacketRentals / Conference & Event Services
I Want To...Access the staff intranetApply for scholarshipsApply to WhatcomCheck my financial aid statusCheck my waitlist statusContact an instructor or staffDonate to WhatcomFind a classFind or post a jobFind an event on campusGet directionsHost an event or meeting on campusJoin friends & alumni programLook up my current class schedulePay onlineRegister for classesRequest a blue slip onlineRequest info packetResearch or check out item from librarySee what programs WCC offersStudy abroadView or order transcripts
Jump to subpage...
About Whatcom+Annual ReportHistory / 50th Anniversary+Whatcom Remembers Harold HeinerMission & Strategic PlanPresident's WelcomeArea Health Education Center for Western Washington+About AHECWWResourcesEducation ProgramsAssessment & AccreditationBusiness & Community PartnershipsCampus Map & Directions+Orca CamParkingCollege Leadership+Board of Trustees+Trustee Meetings & MinutesAbout the PresidentPresident's CabinetOrganizational ChartsContact Us (Remote Services)+Academic Department DirectoryBuilding DirectoryFaculty & Staff DirectoryService DirectoryCybersecurity Center+Academic OptionsStudent Activities and ResourcesInformation Assurance ResourcesOrganizationsWCC Cybersecurity CampNCyTE CenterDiversity, Equity and Inclusion+Black Lives Matter ResourcesIntercultural ServicesEmergency & Weather InfoEmployment / HR+Affirmative ActionApplication ProcedureEmployee BenefitsJob InformationPayroll InformationTitle IX+Equity OnlineProfessional Development+Apply for FundsExcellence AwardsOpening WeekOpportunities & ResourcesProfessional Development DayForms & SurveysRecruitment AccommodationsWellness at WhatcomEmployee Resource GroupsFoundation+Board & StaffWays to GiveScholarshipsStudent Aid+Emergency FundsWCC AlumniCollege HomeNews & Media+COVID-19 Information and ResourcesCOVID-19 Archive InformationPolicies & Procedures-Accessibility at WhatcomBias Incident ReportingBoard Policies & Administrative ProceduresEmergency Info & Campus SafetyIncident ReportingPrivacy NoticePublic DisclosureRequest Info PacketRentals / Conference & Event Services+Request A QuoteSpaces+ClassroomsComputer LabsConference RoomHeiner TheaterVideo Conference RoomLarge ClassroomOrca FieldPavilion (Gym)Syre AuditoriumTheater-style Lecture HallServices+PoliciesStaff Parking & Accomodations
Thank you for visiting the Whatcom Community College website and reviewing our privacy notice. This statement addresses collection, use, and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of Whatcom Community College's website.
FERPA
The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) affords students certain rights with respect to their education records. They are: 1. The right to inspect and review the student's education records within 45 days of the day Whatcom Community College (hereinafter referred to as "the College") receives a request for access. Students should submit to the College Registrar written requests that identify the record(s) they wish to inspect. The College Registrar will make arrangements for access and notify the student of the time and place where the records may be inspected. If the records are not maintained by the College Registrar to whom the request was submitted, that official shall advise the student of the correct official to whom the request should be addressed. 2. The right to request the amendment of the student's education records that the student believes are inaccurate or misleading. Students may ask the College to amend a record that they believe is inaccurate or misleading. They should write the college official responsible for the record, clearly identify the part of the record they want changed, and specify why it is inaccurate or misleading. If the College decides not to amend the record as requested by the student, the College will notify the student of the decision and advise the student of his or her right to a hearing regarding the request for amendment. Additional information regarding the hearing procedures will be provided to the student when notified of the right to a hearing. 3. The right to provide written consent for disclosures of personally identifiable information contained in the student's education records, except to the extent that FERPA authorizes disclosure without consent. One exception which permits disclosure without consent is disclosure to school officials with legitimate educational interests. A school official is a person employed by the College in an administrative, supervisory, academic or research, or support staff position (including law enforcement unit personnel and health staff); a person or company with whom the College has contracted (such as an attorney, auditor, third party servicers such as the National Student Clearinghouse, or collection agent); a person serving on the Board of Trustees; or a student serving on an official committee, such as a disciplinary or grievance committee, or assisting another school official in performing his or her tasks. A school official has a legitimate educational interest if the official needs to review an education record in order to fulfill his or her professional responsibility.
Another exception requires the College to comply with the Solomon Amendment, which authorizes disclosure of "student recruitment information" for military recruiting purposes without student consent. Information disclosed is limited to currently enrolled students over the age of 16 and includes name, address, telephone listing, year of birth, class level, academic major, degrees received and most recent previous educational institution. The College considers name, address, email address, telephone number, date of birth, enrollment status (full or part time), dates of attendance, and degrees/awards received to be "directory information" and this information can be disclosed without consent only if it is determined by a college official that the party requesting this information has a legitimate need for the information. A student has the right to refuse to allow the College to disclose personally identifiable directory/student recruitment information by signing a "Notice of Non-Disclosure" form available at the Registration/Records office. 4. The right to file a complaint with the U.S. Department of Education concerning alleged failures by Whatcom Community College to comply with the requirements of FERPA. The name and address of the Office that administers FERPA is: Family Policy Compliance Office U.S. Department of Education, 400 Maryland Avenue SW, Washington, DC 20202-5920. The College will publish this Notice in its College Catalog and on its public website, and will reference it in its Class Schedule publications.
The College's complete FERPA policy is contained in Washington Administrative Code (WAC) 132U-280.
Information collected
If you do nothing during your visit to our website but browse, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:
The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol Address to direct Internet traffic to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service provider (for example, xcompany.com or yourschool.edu);
The type of browser and operating system you used;
The date and time you visited this site;
The Web pages or services you accessed at this site; and
The Web site you visited prior to coming to this Web site.
The information we automatically collect or store is logged and used by Whatcom Community College only to improve the content of our web services and to help us understand how people are using our services. Whatcom Community College analyzes the website logs to determine how our website is being used, so that we may continually improve the site's usefulness to the public.
What we collect if you volunteer information
If during your visit to our website you participate in a survey, send an e-mail, or perform some other transaction online, the following additional information will be collected:
The e-mail address, and contents of e-mail, for those who communicate with us via e-mail.
Information volunteered in response to a survey.
Information volunteered through an online form for any other purpose.
The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us.
We use your e-mail to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you may identify, to further improve our website, or to forward the e-mail to another agency for appropriate action.
Personal information and choice
You may choose whether to provide personal information online.
Personal information is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.
We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, or completing an online form. You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse Whatcom Community College's Web site and read or download any information provided on the site.
If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.
If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact the Whatcom Community College Registrar as shown in the Contact Information section of this statement.
Whatcom Community College's website is a general audience site and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.
Public access to information
In the State Of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.
All of the information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists. Statue RCW 42.17. 260(1) states that:
Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions of subsection (6) of this section [RCW 42.17.260(6)], RCW 42.17.310, 42.17.315, or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests protected by RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315, an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315 when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing.
In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the agency's disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control.
The complete Revised Code of Washington (RCW) is available at: http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/
Nondisclosure of certain personal information
You may be required to provide certain personal information when you use the web-enabled applications that are described below.
Credit card payment
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to pay tuition and fees over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identify and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to apply tuition and fee payment over the Web, and you will have to pay your tuition and fees in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients; (ss) Credit card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration dates, or bank or other financial account numbers supplied to an agency for the purpose of electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law.
Financial aid inquiry
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your financial aid status over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to give you your financial aid status over the Web, and you will have to obtain this information in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Hope and lifetime learning tax credit
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to allow you to view and copy course enrollment and payment information. The information is required in order to provide you with the tax information needed for compliance with the Internal Revenue Service reporting requirements for the Hope and Lifetime Leaning tax credits. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your enrollment and payment information and you will have to obtain a copy of your enrollment and payment records in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients or public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Registration
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to register for classes over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you will be unable to register for classes over the Web, and you will have to register for classes in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Registration appointment
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your registration appointment information over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your registration appointment information over the Web, and you will have to obtain your registration appointment information in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Schedule planner
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to check requisites while using schedule planner. The information is required in order to access your academic and testing records. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to verify your eligibility for enrollment into certain classes and you may be blocked from enrolling into those classes.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Student address change
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your address over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your address over the Web, and you will have to change your address in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Student PIN change
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your personal identification number over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your PIN over the Web, and you will have to change your PIN in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
PIN management
Whatcom Community College assigns a random Student Identification (SID) number and a temporary Personal Identification Number (PIN) and notifies newly admitted students via an Enrollment Information Packet. Students are directed to change the temporary PIN to a secure PIN known only to them in order to safeguard their student records. The student is ultimately responsible for ensuring that their personal information is secured from unauthorized access by selecting a unique, secret PIN. If at any time the student feels their PIN has been compromised, the student should change it immediately.
Student schedule
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your quarterly schedule. The information is required in order to verify you identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your quarterly schedule over the Web, and you will have to obtain a copy of your quarterly schedule in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Unofficial transcript
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your unofficial transcript over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your unofficial transcript over the Web, and you will have to view your unofficial transcript in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Wait list inquiry
Whatcom Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your wait list over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your wait list over the Web, and you will have to view your wait list in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Whatcom Community College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information at Whatcom includes student's name, address, telephone number, major fields of study, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)
Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Review and correction of personally identifiable information
You can review any personally identifiable information that Whatcom Community College collects about you by using the information in the Contact Information section at the end of this Notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting a written request that credibly shows the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections (RCW 43.105.310).
Cookies
To better serve our users, we are now using "cookies" to customize your browsing experience with Whatcom Community College's Web site. Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your Web browser.
Cookies created on your computer by using this Web site do not contain personally identifying information and do not compromise your privacy or security. We use the cookie feature to store the following information on your computer:
Session login information
Limited personal information, such as name
Security
Whatcom Community College, as developer and manager of this website, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained by Whatcom Community College. These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession.
This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via Whatcom Community College Websites.
Disclaimer
The Whatcom Community College website has many links to other websites. These include links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Whatcom Community College website and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.
Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.
Whatcom Community College reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice at any time by posting such revised Privacy Notice at WCC's home page.
WCC contact information
To review your personal information, or to correct your personal information, make a written request to:
